

Vikram Deshmukh

San Jose, CA 95126 +1 (669) 265-9931 vikram.deshmukh@sjsu.edu

Profile

Front-end Developer with over 9 years of experience in developing Web 2.0 applications for the desktop as well as mobile web with a keen eye for UX.

Avid technology enthusiast; gadget freak; old school PC gamer; loves creating Data Visualizations and developing Apps (for both Mobile & Web), travelling and occasionally reading good fiction.

Skill Set

JavaScript, jQuery, AngularJS, underscoreJS, D3.js

Data Visualizations & Web Apps

• Java, Android, Swift for iOS

Responsive Web Dev, Twitter Bootstrap

HTML5, CSS3

• Wireframing, Prototyping, UML Modelling, Design Patterns

Work Experience 9 years 1 month

Senior Developer(remote) at tPoint Solutions Ltd, Maidenhead, England

May 2014 - July 2016

Led entire front-end development effort of the company. Worked on a low-latency Performance Monitoring Data Visualization Dashboard that is completely responsive.

UI Engineer at ZyFin Research Private Limited, Mumbai, India

September 2012 - May 2014

Designed and developed cross-browser, cross-platform Web Apps and Data Visualizations using macroeconomic data and HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, and D3.

IT Analyst at Jean Martin Systems India Limited, Chennai, India

January 2012 - September 2012

Worked with the on-site development team in building a clean energy setup monitoring dashboard for Petra Solar (one of the industry leaders in solar-energy business in the US).

IT Analyst at TATA Consultancy Services, Mumbai, India

July 2011 - January 2012

Developed Cubbuzz (an interactive advertising-cum-marketing tool with tracking capabilities for analytics) for AXA Equitable and ING Direct; Was also awarded a certificate for my <u>outstanding contribution</u>.

Senior Software Engineer at Geodesic, Mumbai, India

July 2009 - July 2011

As Senior Software Engineer, developed indigenous trading and Portfolio Analytics application for Angel Broking. As Software Engineer, created a comprehensive Wealth Management Application (desktop and online version).

Senior Programmer at Zeus Learning, Mumbai, India

July 2007 - July 2009

As Senior Programmer, led a team (of 3 Programmers + 1 tester) on a large-scale in-house project. Organized recruitment drives, set aptitude test papers and conducted interviews for the employer.

As Web Programmer, underwent training in Web Dev technologies & started working on a prestigious project for Discovery Education within a month of training.

Education

Master of Science in Computer Science

August 2016 - May 2018 (expected)

San Jose State University, San Jose, CA, USA

· CS218: Cloud Computing · CS251A Object Oriented Analysis · CS175-02 Mobile Device Dev

Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Engineering

August 2003 - June 2007

University of Mumbai, Mumbai, MH, India